[breathing heavily]
[panting]
Hey!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
- [groans, panting]
- Hey! Hey!
- What the fuck was that?
- [Lukas] What?
Did they say anything over the radio?
[stammers] I don't... I don't know.
- I don't know. It's not working.
- Fuck! You're shot.
- What?
- You don't feel that?
- Oh, fuck. Help me up. [groans]
- Ah, shit. It went through the radio!
- Come on, we gotta go...
- Oh, fuck.
You're all right. You're all right.
Come on, come on. You're okay.
- [Lukas grunts]
- Watch your step there.
- [Lukas] Yeah.
- One step at a time, all right?
[Lukas] I'm okay.
[groans]
[Kennedy] Come on. Come on.
[Lukas groans] Fuck.
- Okay?
- I'm good. I'm good.
Get the door.
Hey!
- [Lukas grunts]
- [Kennedy] Let us in!
Ah, fuck!
[grunts]
Hey! Hey!
Who are you, and what do you want?
- [Kennedy] Juliette sent us!
- [Lukas] Open the door!
How do I know
you're not covered in poison?
[Lukas] Because I was shot.
If there was any poison on me,
it would've gotten through the holes.
- I would be dead already.
- Open the fucking door!
I got you. I got you. You ready?
It's okay. Come on.
[grunts]
Help me. [pants]
[sighs]
[Jimmy] Okay, so, the bullet
went through the radio and then him.
- [sighs]
- Okay. All right.
[panting] Okay.
Is Juliette okay?
Yeah, of course she is.
She's safe and sound at home.
We're the one's getting shot at
by some fucking thing in the sky.
[pants] Okay. Put-- Put pressure.
[Audrey] Okay.
[electricity crackling]
You know what you're doing?
[stammers] The book does.
[clock chimes, rattles]
- [radio activates]
- [gasps] Hey.
- [static on radio]
- [chuckles]
Go get the other guy.
[sighs]
[chuckles]
- Hey.
- [Kennedy] You fix it?
- [static on radio]
- Yeah.
Do you wanna... Do you wanna talk to them?
- Me?
- Yeah.
No, no, no, no. You gotta talk in code.
It wasn't supposed to be my job.
- No, I... [stammers]
- Do it. [exclaims]
- Do it. Press it.
- I got it. I got it. I got it.
[Kennedy] Hey.
Yeah. Donny, what is it?
Who the fuck is Donny?
Who is this?
[whispers] Oh, fuck. My name.
I don't remember my name.
[mutters indistinctly, inhales sharply]
This is Deputy Calso, um,
here on, uh... Level 17.
[Juliette] Uh, Calso this is, um,
Deputy... [stammers] ...Crane.
- Juliette?
- Please continue.
Deputy Crane? Yeah, okay.
So... So, uh, we had a-a little bit
of a situation here,
but, um, the... the kids are all right.
[Martha] Donny.
Donny, do you hear me? This is Dispatch.
Your delivery is no longer necessary.
Please return to base.
Who-- Who's Donny?
Oh. Calso will you
get off the line, please? Shut up.
- Shut up?
- Donny, did you get that?
Your delivery is no longer necessary.
Please return to base.
[Teddy] This is Donny... It's off.
Returning to base.
[exhales]
Calso. C-Calso, this is, um, Crane.
[stammers] Can you hear me?
[Kennedy] Hey.
Hey.
Really good work on Level 17.
Is Deputy, um, James there?
- That's you.
- What?
You-- You gotta talk in code.
- I don't know how-- [stammers]
- You gotta do it.
- This is Deputy Jimmy...
- Code.
...James.
Hi. I haven't seen you since, um...
since I transferred.
How's the, um... How's the family?
Are they... [stammers] Is everyone okay?
Um... My family,
th-they're doing pretty good.
Okay, great.
And how... Turley...
How's-- How's, um, Deputy Turley?
[Jimmy] Turley?
I got it. Yeah, it's all right.
Deputy Turley had a little bit of a fall.
But he is, um... he's okay.
Okay.
Okay, I'm glad to hear, um...
[inhales deeply]
James, you remember
telling me about your mom?
I'm gonna need you to open up an
investigation into what happened to her.
I wish I could tell you why,
but I don't have time so, um,
Calso will fill you in. Okay?
The digger you saw was the prototype.
Nine more are being built.
Ten diggers to dig
five additional silos each.
Fifty silos in total.
What are the silos for?
Seeds.
Like the seed bank in Svalbard?
[Anna] In a way.
Sorry. Why ten diggers?
So we can dig ten silos at the same time.
Once the digging is complete,
we'll pull the diggers out,
and move them on to the next ten.
In the Army Corps we had a joke...
Does the engineer see
the glass as half full or half empty?
Well, I'm guessing
that the engineer is an optimist.
Half full.
The engineer sees the glass as twice
as big as it needs to be. [chuckles]
- [stammers] You need more diggers.
- How many more?
Well, you want 50 silos.
You need 50 diggers.
Well, I am rich, Daniel, but 50 diggers...
Reusing the diggers makes sense in theory,
but, you know, hauling them up
mile-deep holes costs money too.
Ask your project manager how much
of the expenses the additional diggers
would be offset by just leaving them where
they are when they've done their job.
Fifty silos is a lot of seeds.
[Stensen] Well, not just literal seeds.
We're also going to store the best
of the world's art, literature
and science.
You don't need a no-fly zone
for seed depositories and libraries.
[sighs]
They are also
for a different kind of seed.
People.
To repopulate the Earth.
Repopulate?
[Stensen]
We're facing the end of the world
and it cannot be stopped.
It can only be survived.
[The Algorithm] How do you feel?
How do I feel?
Why? Are my cortisol levels high?
[The Algorithm] You found out
your husband betrayed you.
You wanna know how I feel? I feel tired.
[The Algorithm] That is understandable.
Unfortunately, you do not have time
to sleep right now.
It's four in the morning.
Our airborne surveillance
revisited Silo 17.
The bodies of Kennedy and Lukas are gone.
- [stammers]
- Camille,
you need to find out
the real reason they were sent to 17.
Hey, Pops. Been a long time.
[sighs] How did you find me?
Your friends aren't as friendly
as you think.
What do you want?
[scoffs, chuckles]
Harwood.
He gave you a new life
'cause you built something for him.
All I wanna know is
if he had anything to do
with transporting stolen goods
from Supply.
Get the fuck out of here.
You know...
all my life I've wanted
to ask you one question.
How does it taste?
What the fuck are you talking about?
- [grunts]
- [grunts, groans]
[sighs]
[groans]
[Rick] Hey! Over here!
[Kennedy] Hey, it's over here too.
It goes all the way down.
What is it? [sighs]
I'm a painter and the paint
around this panel has been oxidized,
like it was exposed to heat.
Like, maybe it was welded shut.
I don't see weld marks,
so I'm thinking maybe
it was welded from the inside.
Thank you.
How's Anthony?
Fine.
Almost seems happy to go back
to how things were...
when I came home at night and you didn't.
I've been watching him
to see signs of the forgetting drugs...
Hoping he'll just...
he'll-he'll just forget. You know?
He'll forget this. All this between us.
But I'm dreading at the same time.
- That kid is 90% juice.
- [chuckles]
[chuckles]
He'll be the last of us to forget.
Yeah.
You said there was a way...
to stop Silo 1 from killing us.
[sniffles]
Juliette wanted to send
her friends to the other silo.
Said there were... Said there were
kids there who needed help.
Lukas and Kennedy went instead
and they didn't make it.
- I wanna know why she sent them.
- You said there were kids.
I know what I said. Come on, Rob.
[breathes shakily]
I'm asking you why she sent them.
Why was she even willing
to send her closest friends?
Rob.
You tried to erase
what happened to her there.
But you failed,
just as I hope you'll fail here.
Those kids witnessed terrible things.
And if you can't believe that she
genuinely wants to help those children...
then I don't know you anymore.
[straining] Yep, I got it. Here.
Yep. Welded from the inside.
What?
I'm sorry, Jimmy.
There's a body in a cleaning suit.
[inhales shakily]
She welded herself inside?
Why would she do that?
'Cause she must've known...
We have to move her.
She's blocking the pipe.
Okay.
- Okay. Let's go.
- No, no, no.
People in my silo are going to die.
Like, fucking everybody.
If Jimmy isn't okay
with his mom being moved,
she's not moving.
[scoffs]
Fuck.
Let's just... please.
What do you want?
Your friend Harwood's stealing supplies.
Then why come to me?
I don't know anything about that.
Because you did something for him
that got you out of the mines
and into a whole new life.
I don't know
what the hell he's talking about.
I asked your son for information
about you and he told me to fuck off.
Then, ten minutes ago,
he showed up at the deputies' station,
saying he tracked you down.
Friend said a girl was murdered
and if I could help I should help.
This is the first time
I'm... [stammers] ...hearing this.
I don't know anything about--
Hank and I just found out
that supplies that have been stolen
could lead to us all dying in the dark.
That's so big and so fucked up,
I can't even comprehend it.
But what I can comprehend
is this woman that I met, just once,
she struck me as a good
and thoughtful person,
and all she was doing was trying to find
who was stealing this stuff
to keep us all from dying
and she was murdered.
And I just have a feeling
that whatever you did with Harwood
- played a part.
- Fuck.
[Knox] What the fuck did you do?
Look, unless you killed Orla Kent,
I don't give a fuck what you did.
Whatever I say to you, you promise me...
I don't catch any shit for it.
I give you my word.
[Gus sighs]
We were just bullshitting one night,
having a couple of pops, Harwood and me.
Then I get this idea...
And I shouldn't have said it out loud,
but I did.
Couple of months later,
Harwood comes back to me.
He says, "Draw it up,
and I'm gonna give you a new life."
Did he build it?
Not a fucking clue.
Draw it.
[Bernard] This is Silo 1.
There are seven groups that surround it.
This is our group.
This is us.
Now, if you're Silo 1,
how do you get a poison pipe
to every silo?
I wouldn't send out 49 pipes.
Too much could go wrong.
So, I'd send seven lines,
one to each group.
And then I'd send out
seven more pipes... to each of the silos.
Why build that in, though, hmm?
Why do they need to kill a silo?
I-I don't know,
but we have to at least consider
the possibility
that they have a good reason.
So, then what, we just risk
the lives of everyone in the silo
when we don't even know their intentions?
Yes.
- Why?
- Because if we can cap the pipes
and eliminate their ability to kill us,
then... then we can have a conversation.
And if their reasons for having the power
to kill the silos is sound,
then we will restore the pipes
and drink the waters of oblivion.
But I can't imagine what reason
would justify what they've done.
All the years I did my job...
often doing terrible things...
I always told myself
that what I was doing
was justified and virtuous.
I poisoned... a woman.
A woman... that I loved in my own way.
Mary Meadows.
I was told that her death was necessary
to prevent a silo from killing itself.
[exhales]
But it was all a lie.
I can't make up for what I've done.
But I will do everything I can
to stop this tyranny.
I hate this.
What?
[chuckles] Not hating you.
[chuckles]
What I'm seeing...
is this a reflection of my mood or yours?
[The Algorithm]
Did your husband tell you their plans?
No. But we know
they want to stop the Safeguard.
What I need to know
is how they could do that.
[The Algorithm] I can't tell you that.
Okay.
Okay. Well, then how about
you kill us right now.
Because unless you tell me
how they might do this, I can't stop them.
The threats we face, nuclear war,
climate collapse, viral pandemic,
asteroid strike, artificial intelligence,
and some we haven't thought of.
But the one...
The one that is most dangerous
is also the reason why
I'm the richest man in history.
Nanotechnology.
But not just because it's invisible,
but because I knew... I...
I knew that an enemy government
would soon realize
that a nanoweapon was a hell of a lot
cheaper to build than a nuclear one.
Is there an imminent threat... [sighs]
...from any of these?
The fact that something
will happen is inevitable.
The point at which it's imminent
is not the ideal time
to embark on a project of this magnitude.
The shit you put us through.
We-We thought we were
driving to our deaths.
Yeah. 'Cause we wanted you to understand.
We wanted you to experience
just one of the threats we face.
Why not just tell us?
[Thurman] Because if word
of this silo project gets out,
it could have one of two effects.
Maybe our enemies step down
their efforts toward our demise,
knowing we will soon be able
to sidestep them.
Or they go the other way.
- Destroy it before it's ready.
- Yes.
- Now, in a year or two--
- Or three or four.
When word about what we're
doing here leaks out--
And we'll make sure that it does.
It will be called Stensen's folly.
[Stensen]
And we'll make sure of that as well.
So that the whole world
will just think this is all
a mad creation of a lunatic
with too much money.
Our most fervent prayer is that
this really is Stensen's folly
that will never be used.
But as my daddy used to say as he carried
the biggest damn toolbox I ever saw
to whatever job he was on,
"Better to have a tool and not need it,
than to need it and not have it."
When you say enemy governments,
that includes Iran?
Yeah. Because as I feared,
they created a nano program.
[Thurman] We tried negotiating with them,
we tried threatening them--
And they set off a device
in the Dulles Tech Corridor
to set back our AI and our nano.
Now, we called it a dirty bomb
because people could understand that.
But it was really a nanoweapon.
And it took us to war.
Can we get to what happened
to my squadron?
Your mission helped take out a secret
nano facility Iran built in the mountains
- near the Turkmenistan border--
- Our mission didn't reach its target.
[Stensen] There was a cloud.
The cloud that you flew through,
that was their nano,
and it took over your plane in seconds.
We did not reach our target.
- [Thurman] We had a backup.
- [Anna] Right.
Your friends, Daniel,
in the Army Corps of Engineers
spent two years digging a 75-mile tunnel
from Turkmenistan
to right below the Iranian facility.
The second your squad came under attack,
we blew up their facility
with a low-yield nuclear weapon.
[Helen] Hold on.
You don't dig a 75-mile tunnel
and roll a nuke down it as backup.
The purpose of Charlotte's mission
was to provoke a response,
so you could see how advanced
Iran's nanoshit was. Am I right?
You knew her team would never reach
their target,
you just didn't care because
the nuke was going off no matter what.
- Charlotte, are you okay?
- Which meant that... [scoffs] ...God,
Charlotte and her friends
were nothing more than cannon fodder.
[panting]
[inhales sharply, grunts]
What the fuck
was that supposed to achieve?
- [Anna] Charlotte.
- [Daniel] Charlotte.
That went well. [sighs]
- [Victor] Charlotte.
- [panting]
Charlotte. [panting]
Charlotte, it's okay.
It's okay. Hey. Hey.
- Just let Victor do his thing.
- [Victor] Look at me. It's okay.
- Yeah.
- You're safe. You're okay.
Let's do the exercises, okay?
[breathes heavily]
Hold it. Okay.
- Out.
- [both exhale heavily]
- [Victor] Do it again.
- Okay. [sniffles]
- Okay.
- [Victor] You're good.
- [Charlotte breathing heavily] Okay.
- [Victor] You're okay.
- [Helen] I should apologize.
- Yes, you should.
Just give her a second.
Your sister could do with a memory
of your parents right now.
Oh, uh, sure.
I don't have anything, but um...
You grew up on a farm, right?
- Right.
- Yeah.
It's a two-man job, all right.
- [sighs]
- That's really what it comes down to.
We should both go talk to him,
figure it out together.
'Cause the guy kinda freak--
He creeps me out a bit. He's a bit creepy.
- [chuckles] Patrick.
- He's got the weird eye,
- and the whole thing--
- You can do it.
How the fuck do you know that I can do it?
I don't. I guess I should have said
that you have to do it.
Lukas, I'm not the guy.
You're the guy, okay?
I'm the guy that believed
it was nice outside.
- Okay.
- And--
- And Patrick...
- Yeah.
...you are also the guy who
convinced a lot of people to follow you.
- Exactly. I'm the bullshit guy.
- Yeah.
Yes, so... [pants] ...just go bullshit.
I don't know where he is!
[Hope] I do.
- [machinery whirring]
- [people chattering]
[Carla] Harwood really built this?
- [Paul] We think so.
- [Hank] It would explain a lot.
My father's an asshole
but he's a great engineer.
Then why'd he spend half his life
in the mines?
Because he's an asshole.
Where is it?
[Paul] I heard Orla talking to the mayor
about Construction Supply.
Where? I would've seen it.
It's gotta be outside the wall.
So, there's a door.
We think Orla found it,
and that's why they killed her.
They were afraid
she'd turn them in for stealing.
Just building that
could get them sent out to clean.
[Tess gurgling]
[breathes heavily]
[Kennedy] Hey.
[breathes shakily]
In my silo, people liked
what I had to say about the outside...
and that it was actually nice out there
and we were being lied to.
Total bullshit, it turns out.
[chuckles]
Doris would've laughed her ass off.
When she was alive,
she was the one that everybody followed.
She was the one I followed. [chuckles]
I never convinced her of a fucking thing.
I figure if she was still alive,
she would've...
she would've set me straight.
She would've...
Anyway, uh...
In your silo, do you have any rituals
that you do for when someone's... dies?
I never knew anyone who died...
[stammers]
...until everyone did.
Right.
We do a thing where everyone gathers
in the orchard, all right.
And they... and they put
a, um, a sheet over... [sighs]
...over the body,
and then they lower it into a hole.
And then people say really nice things
about the person who died.
And they take a bite of fruit
and they throw the rest in.
It's... It's nice.
Doris is buried under a peach tree.
She'll never see outside.
But you know,
her body is food for that tree,
and maybe someday the people who
eat that fruit will get to live outside.
And they'll take a little piece of her
with them.
Anyway, I was thinking, uh, that we could...
we could do that for your mom, you know.
'Cause those kids,
they've seen a lot of death.
And I-I just thought
this might be a-a nice way
for them to have a new way
to remember the dead.
You should go with them, Jimmy.
All right? We'll handle things here.
[sighs]
I really wanna know what happened.
Okay.
Yeah.
[breathes shakily]
[groans] Fuck.
Can I get some light? [breathes heavily]
I see the pipe.
It looks like she cut it with a hand saw.
And I'm thinking she used
her welding torch to...
to burn off any of the poison
as she was cutting
until she could weld the cap to the pipe.
I don't know, there must have been more
poison coming out than she expected.
[sighs]
The welding tanks are empty.
- Can you help me up? [grunts]
- [Kennedy] Yep.
- I got you.
- [groans]
Go slow. Go slow.
Your mom realized that
she was running out of fuel, okay?
So,
she decided to weld herself in
'cause that was the only way
she could keep the poison out.
Jimmy, your dad gave his life to save you.
And your mom gave her life
to save your silo.
[whimpers]
[Shirley] According to Lukas,
Jimmy's mom sawed the pipe.
Even with a flame on it,
some poison would escape.
So instead of sawing, we'll pinch it.
The pinch will be air-tight,
but we'll also cut the pipe further down,
cap it,
weld the cap for triple-redundancy.
How do you get to it? They hacked a hole.
[Shirley] Hammer-drill.
[scoffs] That's loud.
[Shirley] Right?
So, we don't try to hide it.
We send someone ahead as a GWP supervisor
to check the work done
by Teddy and his crew.
They say they need someone
to do some drilling,
to stop the level from flooding.
Mmm, that could work.
[Martha] So, who do we send up?
Someone who can pass as a supervisor.
I would,
but I would attract attention, so...
[grunting]
We have moved everything
two people can move.
Maybe it's not in here.
Maybe it is in Critical.
Well, then, let's go to Critical.
If whatever's hiding the door
could be moved by two people,
then it would be easy
for someone to find it by accident.
What's the heaviest thing in here?
- [sighs]
- [knocking]
[Carla] Guys...
Wait.
Knox.
[grunts]
[water boiling]
- Oh, fuck!
- What is it?
[Juliette] I think we sent her
to the wrong panel.
Let's say this is roughly right.
This is where the pipes
enter each of the silos.
So, this is the direction
our camera points outside.
That's the direction that I walked,
pretty much in a straight line.
And when I got to the hill close to 17,
I could see their camera.
It points this way.
[stammers] Their whole silo is turned.
And Shirley's heading here
to open the panel,
when the one she should
be heading to is there.
Okay, I have to stop her.
I apologized to Charlotte for what I said.
I was angry. But I wasn't angry at...
So... [inhales deeply]
I usually try to confine my urge
to speak truth to power
to the people actually in power.
[chuckles, sniffs] Okay. [scoffs]
What?
Oh, that's your setup.
Do you think you're the first journalist
to come at me like this?
Bring it. Knock yourself out. Shoot.
Okay.
How much is this going to cost
to run a year?
The silos are meant to be self-sufficient
- and self-sustaining, so--
- No, no, no.
Apocalypse comes, everything's hunky-dory.
Got it. How about until then?
[scoffs]
Do you even know what a trillion is?
It's one thousand billion.
Right? So, when all the digging
and the construction is finished,
we're gonna put a hundred people
in each of the silos.
That's 5,000 employees,
all making $200,000 a year.
Which is a pretty good salary
for beta-testing a sanctuary.
Five thousand employees.
That's a billion dollars a year
in salary alone.
So, I mean, I'm only gonna be able
to pay for this for a thousand years.
And just like that, another obscene
amount of money is spent on this.
But it's my money.
Not yours, not the taxpayers. Mine.
Could you end homelessness
with the money you're spending?
[scoffs] Yes.
Cure Alzheimer's?
Yeah, I'm pretty damn close.
How about cancer, hmm?
How about ending poverty worldwide?
Look, these are all noble goals, Ms. Drew.
And I hope they're achieved, I really do.
But they're not my goal.
Could I stop this war with money?
Maybe buy Iran. Would we be safe then?
I mean, safe from Iran,
but not from the troll
who lives in his mother's basement
who decides he wants
to hack into missile command
and launch World War III,
or release a virus that
he made with Crispr,
or God forbid, make a nanoweapon for $300
and turns you and-and everyone else
on the planet Earth into gray goo.
Any one of these
is the end of our species.
Okay, okay.
Fine.
So, why are we here?
Hmm? We can't tell anyone, we-we--
Helen, you're here
because we'd like you to join the project.
- [machinery whirring]
- [people chattering]
Thanks. Hey.
Why'd you make me wait?
- We figured something out.
- What?
We had you going to the wrong place.
Come on.
Are you fucking kidding me?
What?
- When were you gonna tell me?
- Tell you what?
You didn't think I'd notice?
My dad was a doctor.
He delivered babies.
Why didn't you tell me?
Because I knew
you'd do what you're gonna do,
which is say that I can't be part of this.
That's not what I was gonna do.
We had you going to the wrong hatch.
Come on.
[Shirley] Fuck.
Is it Knox?
Yes, it is.
Did he take out the birth control
or did you?
- He did.
- He did?
- You would've loved it.
- Tell me.
So we got some stuff from the dentist.
I couldn't feel a thing.
- But he cried and cried...
- No.
...as he was cutting into me. He was like,
"Aw, Shirl. I'm so sorry."
[chuckles]
[device beeping]
[groans]
Oh, for fuck's sake.
[groans] What the fuck are you doing?
I told you to not come up here.
The sheriff is...
The sheriff's what, Mr. Harwood?
[feedback sounds]
[Sandy] This is Supervisor Jenkins.
Did you get the welder I asked for?
Ralf Melby?
No. I've got Shirley Campbell. Why?
[Sandy] Okay. [sighs] She's good.
See you soon.
Who's Ralf Melby?
He's a welder they were gonna send.
[Emerson] Put her in seclusion.
[Anna] Unlike the core hundred
in each silo,
you wouldn't have to live on site,
just within 30 miles or so. Atlanta works.
Helen, that Times job, that is real.
You would be based in the Atlanta office.
When the time comes
to tell the world about the silo project,
you'll be the one to do it.
[sighs] Jesus.
That is a good offer.
But I just... I-I have this feeling
that if... if somehow you're right
about the end of the world...
I think I'd rather be blown to bits
by a nuke.
- Or turn into gray goo...
- [scoff, sigh]
...by nano than stick around
for your post-apocalyptic
underground mole-people party.
Mm-hmm.
- [sniffles] Charlotte, what about you?
- [scoffs]
[Thurman] We could use a good drone pilot.
And Victor has agreed to sign on,
so you'll still be able
to keep working together.
[sighs]
Okay.
[Anna] Daniel, it's obvious
you don't enjoy being a congressman.
You got in
to pass infrastructure reform, right?
This is one of the biggest
infrastructure projects
in the history of the world.
Daniel, if you really think
we need 50 diggers,
I'll get you 50 diggers.
Okay, sorry, do I... [stammers]
...call an Uber, or how does this--
Henry is at the farmhouse,
and he'll get you to a helicopter,
take you wherever you want to go.
Thank you.
[Stensen] And you can keep
the million dollars.
[Helen] Mmm.
Sweet.
Good luck, Morlocks. [sighs]
I need a moment with my sister.
[Shirley] Jules, wait. Can you slow down?
- [sighs] Hey, wait!
- [Sandy] Hey, wait!
I don't have time for messages.
I don't have any fucking messages,
just... [sighs]
I wanna know what's going on.
Billings went to his friends in Judicial
and came back with a name.
Ralf Melby.
What?
That's the name of a guy
that Judicial tried to set up
when Sandy and I worked together, right.
Sandy was warning us.
Look, if she's caught and we run,
they're gonna be after us.
- You have to go.
- We have to go.
No. My shot at getting this done is over.
- You can still get away.
- Fat fucking chance I'm leaving you.
Shirley, listen to me. I don't know
what the fuck I'm going to do.
You have to find another way
to get this done. Go.
Why?
[groans, sighs] Does it matter?
That might mean the difference
between life in the mines
- or going out to clean.
- [door closes]
You think he gets life in the mines
for this?
For fuck's sake.
How long before he's running shit again?
He'll clean.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Look, okay.
You wanna know why?
It started during the rebellion.
I was afraid some assholes
would break into Supply.
So I wanted to make sure that
some shit was safe, like light bulbs.
Not bad. But I don't think
that keeps you from dying on the hill.
For fuck's sake.
And your old man, he was supposed
to keep his fucking big trap shut.
Yeah.
He's a real shit, isn't he?
- But he didn't kill a girl.
- I didn't kill her.
And neither did my daughter.
Gonna guess when she told you that,
she told you who did.
What do you wanna say?
That I'm an idiot for staying?
I have something for you. [sighs]
Something Victor asked me to find.
An old plant.
Smell it. Tell me
if it makes you think of anything.
Please?
[inhales, exhales deeply]
Rosemary.
I mean, why?
The roast chicken Mom cooked
every week for Sunday dinner.
'Cause I insisted.
- [chuckles]
- You insisted? [chuckles] Sure.
Someone, uh, at school convinced you
that Sunday dinner meant you had
to eat the same thing every Sunday,
so we had to eat roast chicken
every week for...
[inhales deeply] ...for two years,
or you wouldn't come out of your room.
I remember her.
[cries]
[Daniel] Move over!
- You gonna try and talk me into staying?
- What?
Are you gonna try
and talk me into staying?
Hell no!
Stensen's cray cray.
No one says that anymore.
They do
if they're really cray fucking cray.
If some mouth-breather does turn the world
to gray goo,
I don't wanna be stuck underground
with Per Stensen and Rosalind Thurman.
I want to turn to gray goo with you!
What? [chuckles]
I wanna turn to gray goo with you! [pants]
[vocalizes] Boom. [vocalizes]
Hank and I told Orla's sister.
What could you tell her?
Just that Mike was stealing shit,
and Orla caught him and he killed her.
Nothing about the lift-thing,
or the light bulbs.
I know it's gonna sound so self-pitying...
but the worst part for me
was going through it all...
alone.
You had Hank and Knox.
I didn't have you.
When I heard over the radio,
Kennedy and Lukas dying out there, I...
I had Sandy and Danny, but...
You didn't have me.
[handcuffs click]
You made your choice.
They got Jules! They got Jules.
[Knox] How?
[panting] I don't know. I don't know.
Fuck.
Go back to the old plan. Blow up Judicial.
With Jules in there?
We have to cap the pipe.
[Martha] Juliette would want us
to do something.
And I don't intend to live long enough
to forget her.